Feeding a hungry world
喂饱饥饿的世界
In 1850, the total population of the world was 1 billion.  In 1930, it was 2 billion.  Today the number is over 6 billion.
一八五零年世界总人口有10亿  1930年达到了20亿  今天这个数字已超过60亿
And it is increasing at the rate of nearly 8 million a month.  Many people think that by the year 2015, there will be more than 8 billion people on the earth.
而且正以每月800万的速度增长  很多人认为  到了2015年  地球上的人口将会超过80亿
Will we be able to feed such a large population?  Already, two thirds of the people in the world do not get enough to eat.  At present, more than 15,000 people die of hunger every day.
我们有能力给这么多人提供粮食吗  现在世界上已经有三分之二的人得不到足够的粮食  目前每天有15,000多人饿死
How can we increase the world’s food production?  Most of our food is produced by farming the land.
我们怎样才能增加世界粮食的产量呢  绝大部分的粮食是靠耕种土地生产的
Some scientists believe that we are only using less than half of the good land in the world.  So one way of increasing food production is to use more land for farming.
一些科学家认为我们只利用了世界上不到一半的肥沃土地  所以增加粮食产量的一个重要途径就是用更多的土地来种粮食
However, as the population increases, more land is used to build houses, factories, shops and roads.  So there is less land for farming.  We have to produce more and more food from less and less land.
然而  随着人口的增长  大量的土地用来建造房屋  工厂  商店和道路  所以用来耕种的土地不断减少 我们不得不在越来越少的土地上生产出越来越多的粮食
There are also other ways to increase the world’s food production.  Scientists are trying to develop new ways of farming and trying to produce more grain on the same land.
还有其他的一些方法可以增加世界粮食的产量  科学家正努力研发新的耕作方法  以便在相同的土地上生产出更多的粮食
They are trying to find ways to get more food from the sea.  They are also developing new kinds of food, such as man-made cheese and meat.
他们正努力寻找从海里得到食物的方法  他们也在研发新的食物品种  如人造奶酪和人造肉
These new kinds of food will become more and more important in the future.
将来  这些新型的食物会变得越来越重要
But the population keeps on growing very quickly.  By the year 2035, there may be more than 16 billion people on the earth.  By 2050, there may be as many as 30 billion!
但是  人口在不断地快速增长  到2035年  地球上人口将会超过160亿  到2050年  人口可能会达到300亿之多
Will it be possible to produce enough food for these people?  The day may come when the world’s population is too big for the earth to feed.
还有没有可能给这些人生产出足够的食物  将来也许有一天  世界人口会多到地球再也无法提供足够的粮食来养活他们